A Guide to the Papers of J. Rives Childs 1904-1967
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Casanova Correspondence 1952-1958
  - Correspondence 1955, 76 items (Box 29)
  - Correspondence 1956, 62 items (Box 29)
  - Correspondence 1957, 185 items (Box 29)
  - Correspondence 1958, 80 items (Box 29)
- Casanova Correspondence 1959-1960
  - Correspondence 1959, 131 items (Box 30)
  - Correspondence 1960, 143 items (Box 30)
  - Correspondence 1960, 160 items (Box 30)
- Casanova Correspondence 1961-1967
  - Correspondence 1961, 263 items (Box 31)
  - Correspondence 1962, 113 items (Box 31)
  - Correspondence 1963, 77 items (Box 31)
  - Correspondence 1964-67, 189 items (Box 31)
- Miscellaneous Correspondence
  - Miscellaneous Personal Correspondence, 36 items (Box 32)
  - Correspondence of Childs with his mother-in-law 1922-1943, 10 items (Box 32)
  - Correspondence of Childs to hs fiancee, Georgina Klokatcheff 1922, 15 items (Box 32)
  - Correspondence of Georgina Klokatcheff, nee Georgina de Brylkine to J. Rives Childs 1922, 6 items (Box 32)
- Miscellaneous Non-personal Correspondence
  - Rumanian Correspondence 1926-1930, 20 items (Box 33)
  - Correspondence with Christian Science Monitor 1923, 12 items (Box 1923)
  - Letters of recommendation 1909, 12 items (Box 33)
  - Letters of recommendation 1912, 8 items (Box 33)
  - Letters, 19 items (Box 33)
    re: teaching at Lawrenceville School
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 116 items (Box 33)
- Personal Life
  - General Biographical Material on Childs n.d., TMs, 3 items (Box 34)
  - Special pamphlet on Childs April 12, 1919, 1 item (Box 34)
  - Miscellaneous hotel receipts, 12 items (Box 34)
  - Materials re: Childs' Military Tenure 1917-1919, 59 items (Box 34)
  - Childs' High School Grade Reports 1906-1908, Printed grade sheets, 2 items (Box 34)
  - Correspondence 1936, 27 items (Box 34)
    re: Childs' illness
  - List of children's books n.d., 1 item (Box 34)
  - Notice of alternative acceptance to West Point July 26, 1910, 1 p., 1 item (Box 34)
  - Harvard materials ca. 1914-1915, 5 items (Box 34)
  - Materials n.d., 14 items (Box 34)
    re: Virginia colleges
  - College examinations n.d., 4 items (Box 34)
  - Awards and certificates 1914-1960, 4 items (Box 34)
  - Foster parent participation 1950-52, 6 items (Box 34)
  - Materials 1914-1967, 39 items (Box 34)
    re: Childs' financial affairs
  - Miscellaneous materials on personal life 1952, 3 items (Box 34)
  - Correspondence, 30 items (Box 34)
    re: Childs' resignation from the Foreign Service
  - Correspondence with wife 1948, 5 items (Box 34)
- Travel Diaries
  - Travel diaries ca. 1915-1918, 15 items (Box 35)
  - History of Romanticism (for Comparative Literature II) 1914-15, Ms (notebook), 144 pp. (Box 35)
  - A. Hyne to Chere Madame [Mrs. Childs] Nov. 20, ____, ALS, 4 pp. (Box 35)
  - [A. Nibin?] to Childs April 7, 1923, ALS, 3 pp. (Box 35)
  - Catalogue of Russian Coins by J.R.C. ca. 1921-23, AMs, 68 pp. (Box 35)
  - Vol 1. "A Cynic's Scrap Book: Being the Autobiography of a Cynic" by J.R.C. Oct. 1915, AMs, 100 pp. (Box 35)
  - Vol 2. "American Ambulance [Service]: Neuilly" by J.R.C. Summer 1915, AMs, 100 pp. (Box 35)
  - Vol 3. (Book II) "A Cynic's Scrap Book" (cont'd by J.R.C. Summer 1915, AMs, 100 pp. (Box 35)
  - Vol 4. (Book III) "A Cynic's Scrap Book" (cont'd) by J.R.C. Nov. 28 1915-Jan. 13, 1916, AMs, 100 pp. (Box 35)
  - Vol. 4 (Book IV) "A Cynic's Scrap Book" (cont'd) by J.R.C. Jan. 14, 1916-Feb. 16, 1916, AMs, 100 pp. (Box 35)
  - Vols. 5-9 "A Cynic's Scrap Book" by J.R.C. n.d. (Box 35)
  - Vol 10. Miscellaneous items ca. 1918, 25 pp. (Box 35)
  - Vol 11. Miscellaneous notes n.d., AMs, 100 pp. (Box 35)
  - Vol. 12 Miscellaneous notes n.d., AMs, 18 pp. (Box 35)
- Miscellaneous Diaries 1913-1960, 50 items (Box 36)
- Genealogy of Rives, Early, Childs, Gee, Binns, Shands, Brown Families
  - Blandford Old Church: Chapel of Ryves Family n.d., Sketch, 1 p. (Box 37)
  - Materials on Early Family 1896-1933, 15 items (Box 37)
  - Materials on Gee Family ca. 1931, 5 items (Box 37)
  - Supplements to Reliques of the Rives 1934-35, TMs, 2 items (Box 37)
  - Correspondence 1929-1943, 60 items (Box 37)
    re: Reliques of the Rives
  - Materials and Correspondence 1929-1945, 46 items (Box 37)
    re: the Rives Family
  - Rives Family heirloom n.d., Photograph, 1 item (Box 37)
  - Miscellaneous Materials on British Rives Family, 24 items (Box 37)
  - Wills of Brown Family n.d., 2 items (Box 37)
  - Short Family Tree of the deBrylkine Family n.d., 1 p. (Box 37)
  - Materials on Childs Family n.d., 64 items (Box 38)
  - Materials on miscellaneous Virginia families n.d., 43 items (Box 38)
  - Materials on Filmer, Brown, Flournoz, Browne, Edwards, Binns, Adams, Green, Leftwich Families n.d., 16 items (Box 38)
  - Materials on Wynne Family ca. 1965 (Box 38)
- Miscellaneous articles and materials on European Countries
  - Newspaper clipping on sinking of Lusitania May 11, 1915, 1 p. (Box 39)
  - Anti-right, anti-business articles 1931-1933, Printed articles, 6 items (Box 39)
  - Articles re: British Middle Eastern Policy ca. 1930s, Printed pamphlets, 3 items (Box 39)
  - Death of George VI 1952, Printed pamphlets, 2 items (Box 39)
  - to Mother re: conditions in Serbia May 6, 1919, TLS, 3 pp. (Box 39)
  - Materials on Serbia 1919, 2 items (Box 39)
  - The Reichstag Fire 1934, Printed articles, 2 items (Box 39)
  - Nazi Germany n.d., Printed articles, 7 items (Box 39)
  - Correspondene with Christian Science Monitor ca. 1927, 27 letters (Box 39)
    re: Rumania
  - Miscellaneous articles by Childs on Rumania ca. 1927, 20 items (Box 39)
  - Articles on Rumania's Dynastic Problem 1925-1927, 11 items (Box 39)
  - Articles on Michael Manoilescu ca. 1927, 3 items (Box 39)
  - Article on the death of Bratianu Nov. 25, 1927, 3 pp. (Box 39)
  - Materials on the Battle of Belleau Wood n.d., 5 items (Box 39)
  - Memorandum on Greece May 26, 1919, 3 pp. (Box 39)
  - Materials on France 1945, 6 items (Box 39)
- Travel Materials for Africa
  - Travel brochures on Africa n.d., Printed pamphlet, 35 items (Box 40)
  - Postcards from African Tour n.d., Printed cards, 125 items (Box 40)
  - Printed Maps of Africa n.d., 7 items (Box 40)
- Travel Materials: Far East and India
  - Far Eastern and Indian travel brochures n.d., Printed brochures, 35 items (Box 41)
  - Photographs & cards from India n.d., 71 items (Box 41)
  - Far Eastern and Indian information n.d., Printed brochures, 37 items (Box 41)
- Travel Materials: Latin America
  - Latin America n.d., Printed brochures, 16 items (Box 42)
  - Printed maps of Latin America n.d., 5 items (Box 42)
  - Latin American travel itineraries n.d., 7 items (Box 42)
  - Postcards from Latin America n.d., 89 items (Box 42)
- Miscellaneous printed maps, 21 items (Box 43)
- Arabian Photographs and Miscellaneous
  - Photographs of Arabian officals n.d., Album, 32 pp. (Box 44)
  - Photographs of Arabian officals n.d., Album, 9 photographs (Box 44)
  - Miscellaneous photographs, 19 items (Box 44)
- Scrapbooks
  - Scrapbook n.d., n.d., 52 pp. (Box 45)
    virtually all items removed except for some Confederate money and some letters
  - Scrapbook of Childs' earlier life n.d., 62 pp. (Box 45)
  - Scrapbook of Childs' earlier life n.d., 40 pp. (Box 45)
- Photographs
  - Photographs from Ethiopia n.d., 55 items (Box 46)
  - Miscellaneous photographs n.d., 44 items (Box 46)
  - Miscellaneous photographs n.d., 27 items (Box 46)
  - Photographs from Iran n.d., 63 items (Box 46)
  - Photographs from Bucharest n.d., 4 items (Box 46)
  - Photographs of Childs in Cairo n.d., 14 items (Box 46)
  - Photo of Foreign Service Class 1923, 1 item (Box 46)
  - Photo of Childs' Army Life n.d., 2 items (Box 46)
  - Miscellaneous photographs of Childs n.d., 26 items (Box 46)
  - Miscellaneous photographs n.d., 9 items (Box 46)
  - Photographs of Childs and Shah of Arabia & index n.d., 9 items (Box 46)
  - Photographs of Washington Correspondence 1921 (Box 46)
- Scrapbooks
  - Miscellaneous scrapbook n.d., 100 pp. (Box 47)
  - Scrapbook containing clippings n.d., 100 pp. (Box 47)
    re When the Curtain Falls
  - Miscellaneous scrapbook n.d., 55 pp. (Box 48)
  - Persian materials I n.d., 50 pp. (Box 49)
  - Persian materials II n.d., 50 pp. (Box 49)
  - Scrapbook of clippings n.d., 55 pp. (Box 50)
  - Photo album n.d., 100 pp. (Box 50)
  - Scrapbook, general materials n.d., 100 pp. (Box 51)
  - Scrapbook, general materials n.d., 100 pp. (Box 51)
- Miscellaneous Articles
  - Miscellaneous articles ca. 1933, 19 items (Box 52)
  - Miscellaneous articles n.d., 8 items (Box 52)
  - Miscellaneous articles of or by Childs n.d., 6 items (Box 52)
  - Miscellaneous materials n.d., 127 items (Box 53)
- Miscellaneous
  - Ribbons and handkerchief n.d., 6 items (Box 54)
  - Miscellaneous newspapers n.d., 5 items (Box 54)
  - Miscellaneous newspapers n.d., 19 items (Box 54)
  - Nazi Attack on Poland September 1939, Printed article, 5 items (Box 54)
  - Miscellaneous newspapers n.d., 13 items (Box 54)
  - Anecdote on Robert E. Lee n.d., TMs, 1 p. (Box 54)
  - Scrapbook containing jokes n.d., 75 pp. (Box 54)
  - Kniga dlia chteniia i beded v shkolakh Vzroslyrch 1921, Printed book, 158 pp. (Box 54)
  - Materials 1924-1945, 2 items (Box 54)
    re: Virginia Historical Society
  - Lynchburg n.d., Printed pamphlet, 48 pp. (Box 54)
  - Mrs. Childs' Crittenton Home work n.d., Newspaper articles, 4 items (Box 54)
  - Richmond Christian Advocate 1934-38, Magazine, 3 items (Box 55)
  - Some intimate facts about Woodrow Wilson April 28, 1921, TMs, 5 pp. (Box 55)
  - Balkans & France n.d., Postcards, 60 items (Box 55)
  - Miscellaneous cards n.d., Postcard album, 26 pp. (Box 55)
  - Miscellaneous cards n.d., Postcard album, 100 pp. (Box 55)